<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Tendayi Kamucheka</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2018-04-14T12:45:06-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tendayi Kamucheka</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Hello World</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/14/hello-world/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-14T12:35:01-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/14/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/hello-world.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hello World!&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about blogging for a while. In fact, starting a blog was one of my goals for 2017. Problem was, I never could come up with something to write or so I thought. Perhaps the time just wasn&amp;#39;t right for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why now? I&amp;#39;ve been writing software for quite a while. To date, I have used programming languages like VisualBasic, R, Prolog, C, C++, PHP, Java, JavaScript, Ruby and most recently Elixir. However, my visible track record shows nothing of my coding adventures. To any person that doesn&amp;#39;t know me personally, it would be easy for them to see me as having not been doing anything related to programming for the last 8 or so years. In this regard, I&amp;#39;m now convinced I&amp;#39;m doing a disservice to myself by not blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason I find myself blogging now is that from time to time I find myself wishing I could have a look at some of my old projects. Whether it is to borrow an old technique or to reuse ideas, I&amp;#39;m finding currently that the more software I write the harder it is to remember my state of mind and or underlying rationale when I did some things in old projects. For me, by far, this is the biggest reason to start blogging. I need to write letters to future me. I need to communicate thoughts, ideas and solutions. I find myself searching Google for things I&amp;#39;ve done before and there just is no reason for that. If I documented most of my projects then I&amp;#39;d know exactly where to look when memory fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, so much for a first rant. Let&amp;#39;s go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
